<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The hue and cry after the priests who wander from benefice to benefice, directed to those who are neer neighbours to the great parsonages, where (if it be possible) they are to be found. It being an ansvver to the Ministers hue and cry; published by a devout clergy-man; R. Culmer. The dialogue explained, the priests dresse pulled off, the speakers, who in the parsons attireing-house were cloathed in a disguise; Mr. Culmers speakers. Paul Sheepheard. Barnaby Sheafe. ... Alias, Paul Sheep-biter; Barnaby Shift; ... hoping the hours approach wherein he shall no longer tythe. The imprimatur saith, let this hue and cry passe, follow it hast; post hast. Let it passe the parochiall, provinciall, classicall combination; but for all your haste, we must examine its warrant, least it be a false pretence, and not sealed with the royall signet of King Jesus. Published by the weakest and unworthiest of the labourers in Gods vine-yard. Charles Nichols.</title>
            <author>Nichols, Charles, fl. 1651.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1651</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 58 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 22 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A52297</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing N1099</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R219332</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99830811</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99830811</idno>
            <idno type="VID">35265</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A52297)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 35265)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2093:09)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The hue and cry after the priests who wander from benefice to benefice, directed to those who are neer neighbours to the great parsonages, where (if it be possible) they are to be found. It being an ansvver to the Ministers hue and cry; published by a devout clergy-man; R. Culmer. The dialogue explained, the priests dresse pulled off, the speakers, who in the parsons attireing-house were cloathed in a disguise; Mr. Culmers speakers. Paul Sheepheard. Barnaby Sheafe. ... Alias, Paul Sheep-biter; Barnaby Shift; ... hoping the hours approach wherein he shall no longer tythe. The imprimatur saith, let this hue and cry passe, follow it hast; post hast. Let it passe the parochiall, provinciall, classicall combination; but for all your haste, we must examine its warrant, least it be a false pretence, and not sealed with the royall signet of King Jesus. Published by the weakest and unworthiest of the labourers in Gods vine-yard. Charles Nichols.</title>
                  <author>Nichols, Charles, fl. 1651.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 18 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for Livewell Chapman, and are to be sold at his shop at the Crowne in Popes-Head-Alley,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1651.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title on p. 1 reads: A rambling hue and cry coming lately to my hand, with this superscription next the imprimatur. Follow it hast, post hast.</note>
                  <note>A response to: Culmer, Richard.  The ministers hue and cry.</note>
                  <note>Copy from Edinburgh University Library (UMI "Early English Books, 1641-1700") has final leaf mutilated at head with some loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproductions of the originals in the Edinburgh University Library and Dr. Williams' Library, London.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Culmer, Richard, d. 1662. --  Ministers hue and cry --  Controversial literature --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Tithes --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Greg Schutz</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Greg Schutz</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:35265:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>The Hue and Cry after the PRIESTS: Who wander from Benefice to Benefice, directed to thoſe who are neer neighbours to the great Parſonages, where (if it be poſſible) they are to be found.</p>
            <p>It being an ANSVVER to the MINISTERS <hi>Hue and Cry;</hi> Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed by a Devout Clergy-man; <hi>R. Culmer.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The <hi>Dialogue</hi> explained, the <hi>Prieſts dreſſe</hi> pulled off, the <hi>Speakers,</hi> who in the <hi>Parſons</hi> attireing-houſe were cloathed in a Diſguiſe; Mr. <hi>Culmers</hi> Speakers.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Paul Sheepheard.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Barnaby Sheafe.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Rob. Rob-Miniſter.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Tom-Tyth-Short.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <p>
               <hi>Alias, Paul Sheep-biter; Barnaby Shift; Rob. Rob not Chriſt's Miniſters; Tom hath Tythed too-long: hoping the hours approach wherein he ſhall no longer Tythe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The <hi>Imprimatur</hi> ſaith, Let this <hi>Hue and Cry</hi> paſſe, follow it <hi>Haſt; Poſt Haſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Let it paſſe the Parochiall, Provinciall, Claſſicall combination; But for all your haſte, we muſt examine its warrant, leaſt it be a falſe pretence, and not ſealed with the Royall Signet of King <hi>JES<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>S.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Can. 5.7.</hi>
               </bibl> The watchmen found me, &amp; ſmot me they wounded me <gap reason="foreign">
                  <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </q>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Micha 3.11.</hi>
               </bibl> The Prieſts teach for hire.</q>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Jude 3.</hi>
               </bibl> They run greedily after the errour of <hi>Balaam</hi> for reward.</q>
            <p>Publiſhed by the weakeſt and unworthieſt of the Labourers in Gods Vine-yard.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>CHARLES NICHOLS.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON.</hi> Printed for <hi>Livewell Chapman,</hi> and are to be ſold at his Shop at the <hi>Crowne</hi> in <hi>Popes-Head-Alley,</hi> 1651.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:35265:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:35265:2"/>
            <head>A Rambling Hue and Cry coming lately to my hand, with this Superſcription next the <hi>Imprimatur.</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">
               <hi>Follow it haſt, poſt haſt.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg> Was ſomewhat ſuſpicious that it made more haſt then good ſpeed, or that it made great haſt to paſſe through mens hands, leaſt it ſhould be over-taken, and attached for <hi>A Cheat.</hi> Wherefore I could not but a little commune with the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer, under whoſe conduct it came forth, and that was the Title of <hi>R. Culmer,</hi> and caſting but a glaunce on the Book, I eſpied a deſigne on foot, or elſe the barne Doors would never have made ſo hideous an outcry; And becauſe I would not truſt the firſt ſight, I looked againe thereon, and at every caſt of my eye, I more and more eſpied <hi>A Prieſt-Craft</hi> therein. I then enquired whence the <hi>Hue and Cry</hi> came, and the three firſt Leaves anſwered me, <hi>From compaſſing the Earth:</hi> and indeed how could the witty Interlocutor ſo dexteriouſly have met with eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Parſons cart, if they had not trotted their horſes to very Jades in ſo <hi>Claſſical a ſervice?</hi> Then I very much deſired to know of what race the Stratagem was, and to finde out its progeny; at laſt it ſeemed to be of the kindred of <hi>Grangrena,</hi> at Ieaſt one of the hand-maidens to that ſweet-lipt Lady; Peradventure it is Midwift into the world inſtead of that Abortive, though often promiſed Rejoynder. But be it what it will be, I ſhall ſend abroad the examination of the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> there produced, that ſo, if you ſhall meet with the haſty <hi>Hue and Cry,</hi> you may underſtand its hidden language. But what need the Author be in ſuch poſt, and ſweat, and froath himſelfe in ſuch <hi>A haſty Outcry,</hi> the harveſt being no nearer? doth he meane to ſet his ſeale upon every tenth Blade of corne as it peepeth out of the ground?</p>
            <p>In the Title Page there be 3 Texts alleadged as witneſſes; The Firſt is, <hi>Mal.</hi> 3.8. which made me almoſt thinke that ſome wandring Jew, bor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rowing the Title of <hi>R. Culmer,</hi> in his pilgrimage to the Temple had fallen aſleep, and being halfe aſleep, and halfe awake, as in a dreame, had cryed out, will you rob God of Tythes and Offerings? For it is moſt evident that this Text refers to <hi>Iſrael</hi> who paid Tythes to Prieſts and Levites, and the Author of the <hi>Hue and Cry</hi> ſaith, <hi>p</hi> 15 We are no
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:35265:3"/>Prieſts, and it is the more ſhame for him that he urges this place, for <hi>Malachi</hi> tels us that the ſons of <hi>Levi</hi> muſt be purged in the third <hi>verſe</hi> of this third <hi>Chapter,</hi> and in the ſeventh verſe of the ſame Chapter, the Prophet tels Iſrael they were gone away from Gods Ordinances, in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtancing in Tythes, and thereupon ſaith <hi>Malachi,</hi> God is robbed. And it was then robbery of God, becauſe of God reſerved the Tyth, when he gave <hi>Iſrael Canaan,</hi> and gave it to the Prieſts and Levites for the ſervice of the Tabernacle, <note place="margin">Num. 28.</note> and in the 10. verſe of this 3 of <hi>Mal.</hi> ſaith the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phet, bring the Tythe into the ſtore-houſe, that there may be meat in Gods houſe; According to that Law in <hi>Deut.</hi> 12.5, 6 and elſewhere; In which <hi>Iſrael</hi> was enjoyned to go to the place God ſhould chuſe, and thither they were of old to bring their offrings and tyths, and there to eat them before the Lord in his houſe, <hi>Mr. C.</hi> knowes the Parſonage Barne is not that Store-houſe God hath choſen no one place whereun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Saints under the Goſpel ſhould bring their offerings. Gods materi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>all houſe made of ſtones, &amp;c. is deſtroyed, and therefore there can be no meat eaten in it, God hath ſeparated no part of our eſtate for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe more then other, <note place="margin">Col 2.14. Heb. 7.12.</note> Chriſt hath taken away that hand-writing off Ordinances, &amp; Saints rob not God in keeping their Tenth; But the <hi>Hue and Cry</hi> committeth a Rape on the Text, adulterating the ſence thereof to ſelfe ends. The next witnes which the <hi>Hue and Cry</hi> calleth in, is <hi>Act.</hi> 5.1. <hi>Ananias</hi> and <hi>Saphira</hi> ſold their poſſeſſions, and kept back part of the price, which very witneſſe doth caſt the Author in his piteous plea for Tythes, for it diſcovers a change of the Law of tythes, ſince the change of the Prieſthood, had tyths been in ſort inſtead of bringing in their poſſeſſions <hi>Ananias</hi> ſhould have brought in his Tyth, &amp; it ſhews a difference between the poſſeſſions of Saints under the Goſpel, &amp; <hi>Iſrael</hi> in the land of <hi>Canaan.</hi>
               <note place="margin">Levit. 25.23.</note> The land of <hi>Canaan</hi> was Gods, and might not be ſold for ever, and the tenth was Gods by ſpeciall reſervation; But <hi>Ana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nias</hi> poſſeſſion was his own, in his own power, as the Apoſtle teſtifies, he might ſell it for ever, Tenth and all; otherwiſe he might colourably have replyed, that the part of the price which he kept back was to ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfie the Prieſt for tythes. But what thick ſcales are before <hi>M. C.</hi> eyes, who hardly diſcernes this Scripture as well as the blind man in the Goſpel did men, <note place="margin">Mark 8.</note> who ſaw them walk, like trees. <hi>M.C.</hi> ſees whole poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſions ſtand like tythes, and tythes like whole poſſeſſions, for by this Text he can deſcerne no intereſt in the truth, but if he will follow the prefident in this 5 of the <hi>Acts,</hi> we muſt bring the price of our whole poſſeſſions, and lay them downe at his feet, and who will be the Level<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler then? But <hi>M. C.</hi> may doe well in his next <hi>Hue and Cry</hi> to declare who ſold him the tenth of their eſtates, and ſtood not to the bargaine.
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:35265:3"/>If he can charge any that profeſſe Chriſt with a Lye, (as that was the ſin of <hi>Ananias</hi>) let them beare their ſin and ſhame; but whileſt he craf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tily ſlanders the truly conſcientious, it is not the fig-leaf of a Dialogue will cover his nakedneſſe, from being an accuſer of the brethren.</p>
            <p>The next place alleadged is, 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 11.26. <hi>In perils of Robbers, in perils of falſe brethren.</hi> It is no great wonder that <hi>M. C.</hi> meets with robbers ſometimes, travelling ſo often between the Committees threſhold and his owne barne doors, ſurely Robbers know fat Parſons, and they can digeſt the price of two or three Tyth Piggs without the thought of Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>criledge; But let me aſſure you <hi>M. C.</hi> if you call the people of God theeves under the flouriſh of a Dialogue; falſe accuſers will one day be arraigned at a moſt dreadfull tribunall, where a Book ſhall be ope<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned more righteous then your <hi>Eaſter</hi> Book, <note place="margin">Rev. 2<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 12. 2 Tim<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </note> out of which they ſhall be adjudged; If falſe brethren were perilous to <hi>Paul,</hi> muſt none of the tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt Miniſters be perilous to true brethren?</p>
            <p>In the next place I met with the Epiſtle dedicated to the Commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tee. In the Front whereof my Lord Generall was fixt, moving the Parliament for the reliefe of the oppreſſed. And Sir, in that motion why moved he not againſt the oppreſſion of Tythes; then <hi>M.C.</hi> cloaths the Miniſters in gay titles as Able, Orthodox, &amp;c. and it is to be hoped that his brethren when their pens are active to reward him, will re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>member the Able, Orthodox, <hi>Hue and Cry,</hi> and ſpread a skirt of ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plauſe upon the Author that he be not naked. But the committee are informed that the Miniſters are the moſt oppreſſed party in the Land, and to prove his aſſertion, he wonderfully argues, that they have ſcores of complaints againſt their oppreſſors: It is as ſoon ſaid, they are the moſt oppreſſing party, and there is as good Logick to prove it, for there are hundreds of complaints againſt their oppreſſions; then <hi>M. C.</hi> ſaith, If he ſhould hold his peace the ſtones of the wall, and beames of timber in the barne would cry: That is if he ſhould hold his peace, and not make ſuch a noyſe, the very barnes would cry down tythes, and therefore the Hue and Cry out cryes them, to drowne their language from being underſtood, then <hi>M. C.</hi> affirmeth; That Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters ſuffer under the people, as they did under the Prelates; But for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gets to enforme us, that the people ſhould be troubled to diſcerne, whether the Biſhops were removed, or no, but that the honourable, and our honoured Parliament commiſſionate not theſe Hue and Cry Merchants to laſh all whom they make offenders at their pleaſure. Then Mr. <hi>Culmer</hi> ſmooths over his owne Pariſh, as if he complained not againſt them, but he limits his encomium with this clauſe, As to late tranſactions, implying that formerly the Hue and Cry might have
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:35265:4"/>hunted for them. But they having done ſufficient pennance, he publiſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth their abſolution. Yet he ſaith, he hath cauſe to cry out againſt one or two, and the tythes of one or two will pay for his three ſheets, ſince they are not ſealed with his Leviticall ſignet for good Church-men; Then Mr. <hi>C.</hi> glories, That his plaine diſcovery of the diſeaſe will pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cure a ſpeedy remedy from the State and Church Phiſitians. And who can dreame of a leſſe effect, ſince the Hue and Cry hath plaid the Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tebanke, and look'd into the Urinall with Spectacles that fit the ſight of old women of an hundred yeare old at the leaſt, and cryed out Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proſie, who judges healthineſſe not by the quality, but by the quanti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of blood; ſtuffe the barne, and the Hue and Cry will ſay all is well, though it be with the moldie bread of Tythes. But this Maſter-peece of wit, muſt be preſented to the Committee, and could the Author do leſſe then gratifie thoſe whoſe threſhold he ſo haunts, with ſome pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>found peece to eternize their names? But let me commune with the Book, and ſoftly whiſper one word into the ear of the Hue and Cry, and therefore <hi>Dromo adeſdum,</hi> ſpeake the truth once, and tell me this <hi>Queſtion,</hi> Why art thou guilded with the name of the Committee in thy Epiſtle? <hi>Anſ. H.C.</hi> Truly, I could never have paſſed from door to door, but every where ſhould have been baited like a Beare at a ſtake, as I do very well deſerve, had it not been for this ſhift; Moreover I am ſent by my ſharpneſſe (if it be poſſible) to whet the Committee to an edge to cut ſome, whom they find not worthy of bonds, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore let me paſſe, Haſte, Haſte, leaſt I come too late. <hi>Reply,</hi> Thou ſhoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deſt have paſſed for me, and I would never have ſpent drop of inke to croſſe thy haſty journey, but that by this Hue and Cry ſo many fowle blots are injuriouſly caſt in the faces of honeſt men, that I could not in conſcience but wipe of thoſe undeſerved ſtaines; And ſo I come to the deſigne of the Author, which in generall is to keep up tottering tythes; and herein I cannot but obſerve, how God hath blinded his eyes, and broken the deſigne in the very management. Indeed Mr. <hi>Cul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer</hi> hath found out a new way of gleaning into his Vintage, the ſowre Grapes of Tythes; for having carryed all he could into his Barne, he hath bound up the rakings in a Book, and its probable he may have a good market for them; many may purchaſe his experiments, to learne thereby to Tythe moſt artificially. He hath laboured to rake every gratten for the Parſon, but he hath taken a courſe to make the boughed Shocke thinner then ever, for he hath taught men (to coſen, as he calleth it in Print) and no queſtion but many may be apt Schol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers, and hundreds may learne by the Hue and Cry, the myſtery of Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing-Short. And this great Ingineer who thought to have undermined
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:35265:4"/>the reputation of good men, and to have conſumed their fame by the wild-fire of his Hue and Cry, hath done little elſe then blown up him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe, and Tythes, that darling of his Boſome in his traine. It is won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derfull to ſee what a profound Student the Author is, in what he calleth <hi>Cheating,</hi> as if he were an old Doctor at it. Surely the aggrie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved Clergie have wrung their hands before this Champion, for the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cay of their Merchandize, he hath notable intelligence from the Barns, how thin they are, and how they come to be ſo ſtarven; he hath regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtred whole leaves full of tricks to teach men to Tyth-Short, and if they be his owne inventions, he hath ſweat faire to teach men ſo com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pendious a way to keep their tenthes, and may commence Maſter of that Art, and weare the Garland before all that ever went before him. But if they be ſtories of what is paſt, the ages to come will be behold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to <hi>M. C.</hi> for ſo painefull a gleaning up, and ſo zealous a recording of the practices of the generation paſt for their inſtruction; and to have compleated the Hue and Cry, <hi>Mr. C.</hi> might have added this out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cry: <hi>O yes, O yes,</hi> If any poore aggrieved Parſon, have complaint to make, againſt thoſe who cannot pay Tythes, let him come to my Court of Records, and now whileſt I am purſuing my Hue and Cry, having Commiſſionated my ſelfe to be chiefe Officer, I will ſet forth his complaint, to the utmoſt power of my Gigantine arme in Print: But I ſhall paſſe over his Tricks, leaving them for any one to improve to the beſt advantage, and ſhall goe forth to unmaske the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>figne further; the Author labouring to Cloake the ſingle-hearted in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentions of men guided by the Word in the ugly and hatefull diſguiſe of Malignancy, Levelliſme, and Prophaneneſſe. And to the tune of this Pipe dances the firſt page, wherein <hi>Mr. C.</hi> clearly hints that the reaſons which move men to act againſt Tythes are: Firſt, that Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters may be their Trencher-Chaplaines; but he is whiſt, and tels us not, whoſe Trencher-Chaplaine the Aſſiſtant to the Dr. of <hi>Harble-downe</hi> was, whom the following ſtory ſo applaudes: then he inſinuates that the Prieſts are hindred from Tythes, becauſe they be Round-heads: But if <hi>Mr.C.</hi> be pleaſed to pull off his Maske, he may ſee that thoſe he calleth Malignants, are the moſt devout Tythe-payers, and they are be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holding to him, for ſo befriending them for their paines, as ſecretly to brand thoſe who cannot pay Tythes, with the obloquie of Malig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nancy. Moreover it is experienced that there be many who although they cannot pay Tythes, yet are as true and truſtie to the State as the beſt of <hi>Mr. Culmers</hi> tribe; and let me informe <hi>Mr. C.</hi> that if ante-Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſme condemne men, moſt of his Coat will fall as ſhort, and ſhorter of praiſe, as thoſe whom he ſecretly beſpatters with Malignancy for
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:35265:5"/>not paying of Tythes; and becauſe it here ſuteth, I ſhall alleadge ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what from the 16. and 17 pages, there being <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ickned <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ins, waxing faint, and feeble, by the ſame diſeaſe; Where <hi>Mr.C.</hi> through the lips of <hi>Tom Tythe-Short,</hi> would perſwade us that thoſe that cannot Tythe it to his content have gotten Mr. <hi>Maligo</hi> to be their Paſtor, and want the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion on St. <hi>Chriſtmas</hi> day, and other Coat-card dayes, and that they feaſt Mr. <hi>Maligoes</hi> Carcaſſe, who preacheth Elephantly, &amp;c. but through this miſt men may clearly ſee, that many who cannot pay Tythes are ſo far from affecting Mr. <hi>Maligo,</hi> that Mr. <hi>Cs.</hi> Tribe ſents the worſe in their noſtrils, for their <hi>Maligo</hi> ſavour, and they do not trouble Mr. C. for his communion, though ſome may expect Mr. C. whole ſervice, who pay him whole wages; And for Coat-card Sermons (to ſpeake in Mr <hi>Cs. owne</hi> Dialect) they ſo ill reliſh them, that they affect thoſe men the worſe, whoſe dreſſe makes them looke like one of the <hi>Coat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cards;</hi> and if <hi>Maligo</hi> men ſpeake ſo Elephantly, we may judge of what Iſland M. C. is, for he hath written very Elephantly, ſhewing a great tooth ready to bite if it were but ſharpened with power; and it is to be ſuppoſed that Mr. C. is not much behind hand for plum-porredge Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons which he ſo accuſes, and though he blame ſome for keeping Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons in the Pickle, yet it is more then probable that he hath ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what in his powdring Tub: and we ſee a Dialogue in brine what Maſters and Dames ſo ever it pleaſes. Then Mr <hi>Maligo</hi> is accuſed for giving the Communion to all comers, like Hogs to a Trough, which thing though it be abominable, yet it would trouble us to reckon how many Swine, M. C. hath fed with that bread, and if that be Mr. <hi>Maligoes</hi> badge, we ſhall finde Mr. <hi>Maligoes</hi> good-ſtore. But I would entreat Mr. C. though ſome ſtand to the corrupt principles, which they have ſucked from the Pulpits, and know not how to break their old wheel-trades to drive after him, but loue their old faſhions where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in they have been dreſſed by Clergy honds, I ſay, I would deſire M.C. with ſuch not to condemne thoſe who have ſhaken off, not only thoſe ſtinking cloathes, but are deſirous to bee ſtript alſo, and that upon Scripture grounds of the old relique of Tythes.</p>
            <p>The next ragg of filthineſſe in which Mr. C. would wrap Ante<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tytheiſts is, Prophaneneſſe; But I am confident ſuch is the guiltleſneſſe of many, in what the Hue and Cry ſecretly charges them, that if they ſhould be covered with the maske either of Malignancy, Prophanenes, or Leveliſme, their honeſt hearts could not know their owne faces in that garbe. Mr.C. addes that no Tyth-payers, are no Sermon men, and that they can well ſpare two things, A prieſt, and a Sabboth. But how can M. C. be ſpared? whom ſhall we then get to write Hue and
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:35265:5"/>Cryes? But many who are dead with Chriſt to Tythes ſanctifie the Sabboth, which they can in no caſe ſpare, and delight in Sermons, though not in thoſe Satyrs and Dialogues which are ſtuffed with ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle ſlanders; Wherefore I could not but ſpeak the truth to their vin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dication, who frequent Ale-houſes leſſe then many of Maſter <hi>Culmers</hi> Tribe, though he would perſwade men that the reaſon they cannot get Tythes, is, their zeale againſt Ale-houſes, and Oaths; I can eaſily think. that Ale-houſes ſhrinke the Tyth-heapes of ſome, but it is be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe they haunt them ſo much: Then we are informed that in the 8. of <hi>Amos</hi> we may ſee the pedegree of ſome men. And in the third of <hi>Mal.</hi> 11. We may ſee the pedegree of others, where we finde that the Prieſts teach for hire, both which together conclude, Like Prieſts, like people.</p>
            <p>The third wound that Mr.C. could give Antichriſts in their reputa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion is <hi>Leveliſme, pag.</hi> 6. where he ſayes under the Title of <hi>Tom. T.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>It goes againſt my will, I meane my conſcience, to pay Tyth rent or Landlords rent, then <hi>Tom</hi> cals himſelf a <hi>Leveller,</hi> which he explains with this profound proverbe, <hi>Joane ſhould have been as good as my Lady, &amp;c,</hi> here to flatter the Committee, and to blinde the people Mr. C. would perſwade that wilfulneſſe was all the conſcienciouſneſſe that men uſed in not paying Tythes; But I here aſſert it, that the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture-guided-conſcience holds the handes of many from paying of Tyths, and I would here at large prove it, but I intend not a volumn here, onely I was preſt in ſpirit to draw my pen through the lines of the <hi>Hue and Cry,</hi> to give a daſh over the head of the ſlanders which I there found, and ſo I humbly refer the Reader to a Booke lately pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed, entitled, A Declaration of the grounds of not paying, and the grievances of many in being forced to the payment of Tyths. And let me aſſure, M. C. that ſuch men defie the name of Levelling, and the gloſſe he puts upon it, which is, To make <hi>Jane as good as my Lady;</hi> If that be the guiſe of a Leveller, then, who be Levellers? When tythes make many a Joane Lady-like, as for paying of Landlords Rent, let their practice comment upon their principle. Are they Levellers, or doe they level mens eſtates? who would not have the Parſons barne level the Country, and be the onely mountaine, and though Mr. C. doth, yet the Goſpel doth not call them robbers, who are not Tythe-payers.</p>
            <p>Thus I have explained the deſigne in generall, and ſo I ſhall briefly touch the Divinity of <hi>Paul</hi> Sheapheard.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Page</hi> 7, M.C. out of the mouth of <hi>Tom. Trumpets</hi> forth <hi>Paul Sheapheard</hi> praiſe, calling him Able, Godly, Orthodox. But if Tyth-divinity be
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:35265:6"/>the Orthodox ſtuffe Mr. C hath to vent, he will ſcarcely be able to prove it godly under the New Teſtament; then Mr. C. calleth <hi>Rob. Robber,</hi> becauſe he robbeth <hi>Paul Sheepheard</hi> of his good name, and by his owne Logick he is a Robber, in robbing honeſt men of their good names, and leaving Malignant and Leveller in their room; Mr. C. ſaith he rejoyceth in <hi>Slaunders,</hi> but it is ſmall joy to ſuffer as an evill doer, I rather thinke by the Hue and Cry, that he rejoyceth in ſlaun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dring. He prints moreover that our Governours know the Myſtery of it, when men pretend they cannot edefie by one whom they chooſe not. The Myſtery is eaſily knowne, to wit, that every Church of Chriſt hath undoubted right to chooſe their owne Officers, then he inſtructs his neighbours, that they cannot put tricks upon the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours; And yet he hath fathered thirty one tricks at leaſt, a whole game of tricks, upon the Committee for patronage, and ſo hath put the trick of an Hue and Cry upon honeſt men. <hi>Page</hi> 8. M.C. aſſerts, that one or two ſway a Pariſh, and ſo do the <hi>Parſon</hi> and <hi>Vicar</hi> if they can. Then he complaines, that ſome be like hounds, that when one yalpes, all open; but we cannot be ſo curriſh as to open in Conſort at the yalping of <hi>P.C.</hi> Blood-hound the Hue and Cry: The reſt of that page is ſpent in a ſtory of an honeſt Miniſter of <hi>Harbledowne.</hi> 1 Of <hi>R.C.</hi> as I ſuppoſe, but the commendation being by his owne pen, I ſhall leave it upon record as the Author hath publiſhed it: This honeſt Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter (but it is ſuppoſed he hath put on his beſt cloathes in the ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion) is called Aſſiſtant to a Dr. <hi>alias</hi> Journey-man Curat: which Dr. is wonderfully applauded, and no wonder, ſince we are ſent to him for intelligence in the <hi>Harbledowne</hi> ſtory. At laſt we are certified, That the good Miniſter went away, and <hi>ſhook off the duſt of his feet a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt them:</hi> and yet I am perſwaded he carryed away as much duſt from them as he could; And where can we finde an honeſt Miniſter, without this badge of goodneſſe, amongſt Mr. C. Tribe? That will not ſhake off the duſt of his feet againſt a ſmall living, to thruſt them up to the knees into the mire of a great Parſonage. But we are told it was done willingly on the Miniſters part; yet it ſeemes he had not the peoples wils to ſtay any longer. In the ninth <hi>page,</hi> Mr. C. cavels againſt free maintenance; where he ſaith, <hi>That the Diſciples were to heale di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeaſes freely,</hi> then he affirmes, that their bodily cures could not but eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry where bring them in plenteous proviſion, then he addes, <hi>That they were as ſheep among Wolves.</hi> And how could they be ſo plenteouſly provided for, and yet be among Wolves? how could they heale di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeaſes freely, and yet ſell their cures? He addes, <hi>Theſe things are ceaſed.</hi> But their chiefe worke was to preach the Goſpel, and their incou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ragement
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:35265:6"/>therein, was, what was freely communicated to them, <note place="margin">Luk. 8.4 Phil. 15, 16.1 Rom. 15 27. 1 Cor. 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 2.</note> and there is not one clauſe of Goſpell that ſhews us, that this free mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance was to ceaſe, or to be exchanged for a forc'd maintenance; nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther was it changed, untill Churches grew corrupt. <hi>M. C.</hi> documen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſeth us, <hi>That maintenance is as due to the Miniſter, as hire is to the Labou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rer;</hi> ſo it was of old, and yet it was left to the people to contribute, as God moved their hearts. But by what new ſound Law or Oracle would Mr.C. perſwade men, that they muſt pay thoſe who doe no worke for them, he would have men pay thoſe whom they never hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, and though they doe labour to pull downe Chriſts buildings, yet he would have them paid: The labour it ſeems muſt be conſidered, though it be a labouring to deſtroy: But he that ſets ſome at worke will pay them their wages. Neither doth Chriſt hire his labourers with Tythes. Maintenance indeed the Goſpell allowes, and it is ſo a debt that it is free, and ſo free that it is a debt, as ſaith the Apoſtle, <hi>Rom.</hi> 15.27. It hath pleaſed them of <hi>Macedonia</hi> and <hi>Achaiah</hi> to make a contribution, <hi>ver.</hi> 28. The Apoſtle addes, their debtors they are, gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving us the reaſon, to wit, they had been made partakers of their ſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rituall things; where we ſee it was a debt, and it was due for ſpiritu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>als, and to diſcharge this debt it pleaſed them to contribute, and they contribute what they pleaſed; no bounds were ſet them, no out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward force compel'd them. He that receives ſpirituals, owes carnals, but it is left free, neither doth the Goſpel determine, how much he ſhall pay.</p>
            <p>Neither can I ſee any warrant to call in earthly power to force men to contribute more then they be free, <hi>Act.</hi> 5. the Apoſtle told <hi>Ana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nias</hi> that it was in his owne power, if he had not brought it, it ſhould not have been compelled from him, <note place="margin">2 Cor. 9.6, 7.</note> he doth not ſay it was in <hi>Caeſars</hi> power, but in the power of the Donor. Indeed we are enjoyned, not to ſow ſparingly, but note the penalty, which is, leaſt you reape ſpa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ringly; it is not added leaſt the Magiſtrate turne Chriſtian, and force it with damage from you, the next verſe croſſeth that, where it is ſaid; God loves a cheerfull giver, yea, and he hates a grudging giver, and to force a man by earthly power to give, who grudges thereat, is to force him to do what God hates. But Mr. C. to ſpeake like him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe, that every ſentence might beare his image in its forehead, addes, That mens free benevolence is a Wolfiſh benevolence. And is not the Parſons ſpirit a wolfiſh ſpirit, who if men will not feaſt him, will devoure them; then he tels us that Chriſt found ſuch a wolfiſh bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>volence: but he may bluſh at that drop of his pen, ſince neither Chriſt nor his, never went about to force better entertainment by worldly
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:35265:7"/>weapons, and would, M.C. be better then our Lord and Maſter, or doth he thinke now nothing to good for him, ſince he hath ſent his Hue and Cry abroad to proclaime his fame? The next thing which is abomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation in his eyes is, working with his hands; yet I ſhould be ſorry to ſee M.C. have power to ſlaſh all whom his Hue and Cry perſues, fearing leaſt he worke, and belabour them with hands and feet too. But M <hi>Culmer</hi> ſummons us to diſtinguiſh between the Church in pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſperity, and in perſecution, the diſtinction is too too cleare. For the Churches under proſperity began to be Anti-Chriſtian, and to lay the foundation of their Kingdome in the world, whereas under per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecution they were pureſt, and were beſt content to follow the Lord in his leading footſteps.</p>
            <p>Then M.C. grants, as being not able to deny. That <hi>Paul</hi> would not abuſe his power, by being chargeable, where it could not be with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out oppreſſion to the diſtreſſed; And by that grant, multitudes are judged, who though Chriſt give them no power to live of Tythes, yet they abuſe the power they pretend to, in being oppreſſors to the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſſed. For the Prieſt will have from poor men, tyth, who can hardly keep a Cow to feed their infants with milke, yea, the tenth egge muſt not eſcape his fingers, though a poore mans child want it to make a meale, and ſuch like things Mr. Vicar cals his privy Tythes. I do be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that the Goſpel allowes a Goſpel Miniſter, to accept of a liveli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood, as due for Goſpel ſervice, in the way of the Goſpel; but I can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not meet with Scripture or reaſon, that ſhewes they ſhould live of the Alter. Then Mr. C. addes, that he is not one penny charge to <hi>Robin</hi> the Farmer for tyths, and other duties, and that he receives none of his temporalls; which is ſuch a riddle, that M. C. muſt charme up <hi>Edipus</hi> to uphold it; Doth he meane that he hath none of <hi>Robins</hi> temporalls, becauſe <hi>Robin</hi> keeps his tythes himſelfe? or doth he meane he hath none of his temporals, adjudging tythes not to be temporals but ſpiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuals? or doth he meane they are not his, but Gods, becauſe in the firſt page we are told that God is robbed? but ſurely the man meanes the Tythes are not the Farm<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>s, and if they be not his; how can he pay his debts to the Prieſts (as they call them) with them; the rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon is given; Becauſe the Farmer payes ſo much the cheaper for the Land, and hires it upon that condition. I never ſaw a Leaſe yet expreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing that condition, and if it be implyed, what a ſnare is it, that men cannot follow their callings without ſuch a burden? that a man may not hire a piece of land without that bondage which grates his conſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence, and grindes his Family. But is the Parſon no charge to the Far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, <hi>monſtrum horendum;</hi> though the Land be his Landlords, yet the
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:35265:7"/>ſeed is his owne, either paid for, or to be paid for. The tillage his owne, the mending of that Land his owne, the harveſt his owne, the ſervants and ſtock his owne; and if <hi>M.C,</hi> can teach the farmer to doe all this without charge to him, it would have gotten him more re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect then his Hue and Cry, and the tenth ariſeth out of all this; the Land will not bring forth alone. Tythes are ſo chargeable to ſome that they almoſt beggar them, I might have ſaid altogether. A poore Farmer may owe for his ſeed, and plough and dung his land at great coſt, and at harveſt, his crop may not be much more then he ſowed, beſide all other charge, and yet what the Canker, and Crowes, and Rookes, and Dawes have left, the Parſon will Mildew, though the Landlord have as much rent as the Land is worth without Tythes, But the Prieſt is no charge it ſeems, the tenth Sheaf is dung it ſeems enrich<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Land, <hi>Contus contrarium verumeſt;</hi> But <hi>M.C.</hi> triumphs, in that Tythes were before <hi>Levi.</hi> So was circumciſion, <note place="margin">Gal. 5.4, 5</note> the ſame <hi>Abraham</hi> in whoſe loynes <hi>Levi</hi> paid Tythes, circumciſed <hi>Iſaac,</hi> ſo was cleanes and uncleaneſſe of beaſts, &amp;c. in <hi>Noahs</hi> time; and yet they are ceaſed, and he that is circumciſed makes Chriſt of no effect; we are informed that Tythes were Gods way: &amp; ſo was circumciſion, ſo was cleanneſſe and uncleanneſſe, but now they are not owned by God being aboliſhed. If Tythes were the way of God for Goſpel Miniſters, then Chriſt, and the beſt of Goſpel-Miniſters were out of Gods way, who tooke none. But M.C. alleadges that Chriſt approved of Tythes, <hi>mat.</hi> 13. But to whom was it approved? even to the <hi>Phariſees,</hi> and is M. C. one of the Sect? But Chriſt had not then altogether fulfilled the Law, and ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rogated the ceremonies thereof; and ſince his death and reſurrecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, we have not the leaſt tittle of approbation thereof, either by Chriſt or his Apoſtles. M.C. produces, <hi>Gal. 6.</hi> where he that is taught in the word is to communicate to him that teacheth him in all good things. But no man is enjoyned how much, but therein is left free, neither is any one engaged to communicate to him by whom he is not taught; Then M.C. cals for the Magiſtrate to puniſh evill doers, but cannot prove the non-payment of tythes to be an evill deed, and to encou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage them that doe well; and do not they do well, who deſire that the ſlaine ceremonies may be buried in Chriſts grave, and much better then they who would rake them out? Then to ſound the profundity of his braine, he cronicles, That one may do a duty freely, <note place="margin">1 Cor. 7.23.</note> though the Magiſtrate command it, but a man fearing God muſt not ſin againſt his duty of God, by the commands of what men ſoever, ſince we find our ſelves in the Goſpel, neither enjoyned by duty to pay tythes; nor
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:35265:8"/>liberty left us to revive the dead ceremonies of the Law, we canot free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly betray our conſciences in offering ſuch a ſacrifice; M. C. demands, if they that rob him againſt Law, will freely maintaine him without Law: If he be a Miniſter of Chriſt he muſt have recourſe to the Goſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel for maintenance, and if Saints embrace him as ſuch an one, they will and ought to maintaine him without mens Laws. It is next as<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked; Whether the prophane and hereticall will maintaine Orthodox Miniſters. I would gladly ſee where the Goſpel expects from ſuch Minſteriall maintenanance, whileſt ſuch. Muſt Chriſts Miniſters be fed out of the troughs of Swine, Mr. C. told us even now, that the Preacher of <hi>Harble-downe</hi> ſhook of the duſt of his feet, and I am confi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent ſuch a practice is more juſtifiable from Scripture, then to force tythes from them who deſpiſe both Miniſters, and Miniſtry. Then Mr.C. argues, that if Miniſters muſt be maintained by voluntary con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tribution, that they will be enſnared to daube up thoſe people; and the ſame argument holds, that if ſome men ſettle on them Tyths, that they will daube them to keep their Leviticall Patrimony, and do they not bravely daube, and greaſe their Patrons, whoſe ſervants, orators flatterers they will be, and theirs for a Preſentation: Then the man not without a notable forehead publiſheth, That hereſies will abound as in <hi>Pauls</hi> time, if there be not ſetled maintenance. This is a gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lant ſtraine, and had need be powdred up for feare of ſavour; can a man be ſo wilfully blind, as ſecretly to charge the hereſies in <hi>Pauls</hi> time upon the want of ſetled maintenance; but he can ſee as well through a ſtone-wall, as through a Tyth-ſhocke? doe ſetled riches preſerve from hereſies? or rather are they not the poyſon of Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>es? as <hi>Auſtin</hi> ſaid, <hi>Religio peperit divitias, &amp; filia devoravit matrem.</hi> It would pleaſe the Parſon well to have the Church planted in <hi>Dives</hi> his Family, and to have <hi>Lazarus</hi> excommunicated. Can an earthly Law preſerve from hereſies, more then that Apoſtolical ſpirit which breath<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in <hi>Pauls</hi> time? who are fuller of hereſies then the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Synagogue, and yet who ſwimme more in Tythes, and other riches? Nay the Whore <hi>Rev.</hi> 17. hath her abominations and filthineſſe of fornication poured into a Golden Cup. If forcing of tythes will drive and keep out hereſie, it verefies the old Proverbe; that one heat will drive out another, one hereſie another. We are told Chriſt paid tribute, what is that? ſince he, nor his tooke no tythes, muſt all the Land be tributa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry to the Prieſt, have they conquered us into a vaſſallage? Then he ſaith, Tythes be due by a Civill Law, even now, he brought forth the old Law of God, which is changed, and told us of robbing God.</p>
            <p>Then he perſwades himſelfe, that none can deny, but that Tythes
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:35265:8"/>be the equalleſt way; it would be worth ſeing, if he ſhall call forth but halfe ſo many arguments to back his aſſertion, as their be men, who upon demonſtration can ſhew, that there is no equality in them. Why ſhould a poor farmer pay more then a rich Landlord, or a great Shop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keeper? Then <hi>M.C.</hi> ſaith he hath as much right to the tenth part as the owner hath to the nine, that muſt be underſtood, he as a Miniſter hath this right. But till he can ſhew where the Goſpel enrights him to the tenth, he muſt give men leave to be at their choice whether they will beleeve it or no.</p>
            <p>In the next place, Mr.C. doth not love to heare of going to another pariſh to be paid better, which is a ſure marke of a good benefice. He ſaith, ſo to do would make Miniſters Runagates; But who made a runagate of the good man of <hi>Harble-down,</hi> and of other, who poſt from Benefice to Benefice for gaine. Now the feet which could ſhake of duſt againſt a ſmall living, are ſunke ſo deep in the mire of Tythes that they muſt not be wagged; then we are told, that Chriſts owne would not receive him. But he did not force himſelfe upon them, which he might have done, with much more reaſon then Mr. <hi>Culmer,</hi> ſurely he cannot challenge whole pariſhes to be his owne, if he can, he were beſt claime the firſt borne, and to take the price of redemption, which was in force when tythes were, <hi>M.C.</hi> tels us it is a prejudice to their Miniſtery to be in and out. Poor men they be aſleep and dreame not of this thought, when the great Barnes cry <hi>Come,</hi> then the <hi>Eccho</hi> is, <note place="margin">Num. 18.5</note>
               <hi>Here we be, how ſhall we get in?</hi> Then if they or theirs, be Coſen to a Patron, or a Committee man, or the like, or acquainted with them, they run to them to helpe them obey the call of the Barne, which in no caſe will goe out of their eares,</p>
            <p>In the 13. page <hi>M.C.</hi> would turne oppoſition of Miniſters into op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition of State, as if Miniſters were the States Embaſſadors. And to applaud the Civill Seal, which he glories to have received to his Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtry; he expreſſeth that the Scripture ſpeakes of ſending, But the New Teſtament ſpeaks not of earthly Kings ſending of Goſpel-mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters, the Lord of Lords, and King of Kings ſends his owne Embaſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dours; and to fill up the Epha of guile Mr. C. addes, that ſome would would be ſubject in nothing, meaning thoſe that cannot pay tythes. A pure Neronian blaſt, fit language for the Hue and Cry, juſt as if of old they ſhould have ſaid, becauſe <hi>Paul</hi> bid us not be ſervants of men, and to ſtand faſt in our liberty, in which Chriſt hath made us free, This <hi>Paul</hi> whom they called <hi>Peſtilent fellow,</hi>
               <note place="margin">1 Cor. 7.23. Gal. 5.3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</note> would have us ſubject in no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing. But let me tell M.C. that we can freely give to <hi>Caeſar</hi> the things which be <hi>Caeſars,</hi> though we dare not make the Commandement of
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:35265:9"/>God of no effect by Tradition, being taught that they worſhip God in vain, <hi>who teach for doctrines the commands of men,</hi> Mat 15.6.9. Then M. C. as if he knew the way, plainly affirms, <hi>That ſome will go to hell to ſave charges,</hi> paying of tyths will not keep men out under the Goſpel; ſome men have bought hell with money, in thinking to buy heaven, in gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving great ſums for buls, pardons, diſpenſations. Then <hi>M.C.</hi> diſlikes that any ſhould ſay they hear him not, &amp; therefore need not pay him tyths, becauſe they may heare if they will, but ſome cannot communicate with the Pariſh Parſons, ſome again have land in three Pariſhes, and cannot partake of ſpirituall from them all, by the Pariſh account, and yet they all will claim temporals. Then he tels us, <hi>that Mrs. complains of ſervants now they are not compelled to go to Church at home;</hi> he hath not for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>got, that when men were ſtrictlieſt bound to their Pariſh Church, as he calleth it, that then there was ground enough to complain of ſervants, and maſters alſo, when was there more ſporting on the ſabboth, &amp;c. <hi>M.C.</hi> would never think of ſlaſhing thoſe to pariſh aſſemblies, who in conſcience cannot joyne there, but are led by an enlightned conſcience to ſpend the Lords day elſwhere to their ſouls edefying, according to Gods word, but that he wants their tyths, as if ſuch an offering would expiate any ſin. Then <hi>M.C.</hi> to perſwade men to pay him, tels them they <hi>have paid tyths to popiſh Prieſts, &amp; altar Prieſts,</hi> and hath he not as much right to them as they; what goodly preſident <hi>P. Sheepheard</hi> hath got<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten: Then we are aſſured, <hi>that the Parliament will not bee companions of Theeves, nor guilty of other mens ſins:</hi> Many rejoyce at it that our worthies will not force men to pay tythes, who in conſcience cannot pay to whom it would be a ſin to pay; <hi>what is not of faith is ſin.</hi> Then he que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, <hi>Whether we think their will be a failer of Juſtice in Parliament?</hi> Truly, many hope not, and for all M.Cs. accuſations, they hope to ſee their righteous tranſactings in removing of tyths. Then he publiſheth, <hi>That combination againſt Law is ſedition.</hi> But when they wanted the Biſhops down who were eſtabliſhed by law, that they might get in their rooms, then it was not ſedition in them for to move againſt them. Then they pleaded to be eaſed by the Parliament in the correction of the oppreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing laws, and that is all the combination againſt law that I know ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt men to uſe in reſpect of tyths; even humbly to deſire the Parliament to repeal that Law, which enforceth conſcientious men againſt their conſciences. But he cavels at holines next, with this Queſt. <hi>Is fraud ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lines?</hi> as if not to pay tyth could be accounted fraud, then we are told, <hi>That theſe are times of diſcovery.</hi> Many of <hi>M.Cs.</hi> tribe have proved it true, in ſhewing what they are. Then he declares <hi>That a good man is a Law to himſelf, when he can do evil without danger of law, and that tyth-robbing hath
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:35265:9"/>ever been the badg of a Knave.</hi> But why doth <hi>M.C.</hi> put light for darkneſſe, and darkneſſe for light; May any by Law continue what Chriſt hath aboliſhed? can the law of man make that good which is not good? though a good man be good without law, yet he cannot be evil by law Who doth <hi>M.C.</hi> call <hi>Tyth-robbers,</hi> they who take tyth, where men can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not pay tyth, or thoſe who pay no tyth. If a man be a knave for not paying tyth, then is he a knave for following of Chriſt and his Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles, and the Saints in the Primitive times, who neither took nor paid any; it is to be hoped that the next book <hi>M. C.</hi> publiſheth will be a Callender full of new holidays, where we may look to ſee Tyth-pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers cannonized for ſaints, and feſtivals to be kept, if not for their ſakes, yet at their coſts. But no men ſpeak ſo much unlike <hi>Peter</hi> as they that pretend moſt to <hi>Peters</hi> Chair; and what man can ſpeak more unlike <hi>Paul</hi> then he that pretends to the name of <hi>Paul Sheepheard?</hi> Doth <hi>Paul</hi> ſay, <hi>It is the badg of a Knave not to pay tyths?</hi> No, no, this is ſome of the <hi>Hue &amp; Cry Orthodox divinity,</hi> and the vomit of <hi>M.C.</hi> ſtomack, who further ſays; <hi>That he that makes no conſcience to pay tyths and other duties to the Min<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, will be found unconſcionable in all his dealings when he hath advantage, whatever fair pretence of conſcience he make M. Cl.</hi> dialogue will not waſh away the blot which this foul ſlander caſts upon his name; but becauſe he ſaith it is matter of his own obſervation, it is the leſſe wonder, becauſe he looks on ſuch men through the ſpectacles of prejudice; but however <hi>M.C.</hi> overlook'd them; there be many that cannot pay tyths, who have as few motes in their eyes as himſelfe, and ſhew as great a conformity to Chriſt in the whole courſe of their converſation as he doth, or can do. Mr.C. <hi>accuſed ſome to be enflamed with helliſh Covetouſnes.</hi> When, or from what pit aroſe thoſe ſparks which have enflamed <hi>M. C.</hi> tongue that it ſcorches ſo hotly in theſe fiery fire revilings. Then he ads <hi>It is but a figleafe to cover the withholding of tyth, under pretence it is but tyth:</hi> and when Chriſt who judgeth righteouſly ſhall appear, I doubt it will prove little better then afig leaf to many, to cover the coveting of their neighbours goods, under pretence that it is tyth. Then to ſtrike at the very root, we are told, <hi>That it is the depth of Satan to ſet pretenders to new light ſeekers, &amp;c. to quench the light of the Goſpel by taking away the liveli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood of the Miniſter;</hi> which brings to my mind that paſſage concerning Satan, of whom it is ſaid, <hi>That he ſhull rage, having but a ſhort time;</hi> what can be foamed out more againſt the people of God, then may be found in the <hi>Hue and Cry</hi> of <hi>P.S.</hi> As for the light of the Goſpel, it is of a more divine nature then to be quenched by the decay of the oyl of tyths; and it did ſhine brighteſt when it had none of that forraign fewel: and when lamps have been fulleſt of that oyl, the light of the Goſpel hath been
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:35265:10"/>moſt thick and cloudy, and filled with the ſnuffie ſtenches of domineer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing humane inventions. To <hi>M.C.</hi> next leaf I have replyed, in the be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning of my anſwer, only I ſhall quote one clauſe of the <hi>H. C.</hi> then paſſed over, which is this; <hi>M.C.</hi> affirming, <hi>That Gods word and not our rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons muſt be the rule of our life and converſation,</hi> I would <hi>M. C.</hi> would have the ſent of that notion in his noſtrils when he hunts after tyths, and meaſure out his maintenance by the line of the Goſpel. Then <hi>M.C.</hi> tels us, <hi>That Barnaby Sheaf,</hi> to wit the <hi>Impropriator, wonders why men be ſo obſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate as not to pay tyths;</hi> and may he not wonder whoſe eyes be daubed up through partiality and intereſts, all the while in the Dialogue, <hi>Barnaby</hi> ſtood mute, and now is called forth inſtead of a Clerke to ſay <hi>Amen,</hi> to <hi>P. Sheepheards</hi> Orthodox ſtuffe. Now he can ſing in tune with <hi>Paul Sh.</hi> and ſay, <hi>Men are unperſwadeable by clear light and reaſon:</hi> But where ſhall we find that clear light and reaſon, the <hi>Hue &amp; Cry</hi> only groaps in the dark, or doth the clear light and reaſon ſhine in the firmament of <hi>Rome?</hi> But a candle of their owne making will give light enough to ſerve their turn. Then <hi>Bar. Shea. Paul Shep.</hi> brother in law ſaith, <hi>his eſtate lyes in tyths;</hi> &amp; can it lye worſe? <hi>he is unwilling to be undone;</hi> O that he were ſo unwilling to undoe others. Then he ſaith, <hi>that parſonages have been bought and ſold,</hi> the more is the pity, that poor mens labours and eſtates ſhould be bought and ſold, and ſome have got by the bargain, thoſe who have not may be ſatisfactorily conſidered. But not being able to hold longer, he is ſo anointed with the ſpirit of <hi>hue and cry love,</hi> that he breaks forth crying <hi>for whips and cords,</hi> ſaying, <hi>treble damages are too liltle; O brave Paul!</hi> this is your conſcionable and Orthodox Divini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty. <note place="margin">
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ox 118.</note> Surely the Parſons mind is a bottomleſſe gulph that it can ſwallow up more then treble damages. <hi>M. C.</hi> is leſſe charitable then <hi>Gregory</hi> of <hi>Rome</hi> was who told <hi>Auſt.</hi> that the Church ſhould not require increaſe, what was ſtoln away in earthly things, and ſeek her own good, by the damages of others. But the <hi>hue and cry</hi> can do nothing without a ſlaſh. Then <hi>M.C.</hi> demands, <hi>Why the Parliament enjoyn tyths?</hi> truly it is the hope and deſire of many, <note place="margin">
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>eb. 10.34</note> that the Parliament will not enjoyn them; howe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver they muſt chuſe rather to ſuffer then to ſin, <hi>M C.</hi> ſaith <hi>Some of them make briek and have no ſtraw.</hi> What hath <hi>M C.</hi> ſo many heaps of corn, and no ſtraw, hath he found out by Chimiſtry to turne his ſtraw into Wheat? If he have no ſtraw, it is pity that he goes not out of <hi>Aegypt,</hi> and leave his ſtraw maintenance he looks for; if he were to ſpend the ſtraw he hath in brick making, we ſhould hear another tune: he ſaith alſo, <hi>That ſome of them can glory more then</hi> Paul, <hi>he preach't for nothing, and they for leſſe then nothing;</hi> will any man in the world beleeve it? he that can ſtretch his faith upon the tenter-hook of that expreſſion, I will
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:35265:10"/>warrant him, it will be a ſufficient ſize to reach to the bottom of any old wives fable; is 50. or 1, 2, 3 hundred pounds a year nothing, yea leſſe then nothing, a competent number of ſuch devourers, who can ſwal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low two or three hundred a year, and judge it nothing, through the wideneſſe of their throat, will eat up and beggar a Iſland. If <hi>M. C.</hi> can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not get ſome tyth in, yet he cannot glory as could <hi>Paul,</hi> for it is againſt his will he fals ſhort of an ear, we ſee he ſends <hi>hue and cry</hi> after the looſe eares, but what <hi>Paul</hi> did he did voluntarily: then he complains, <hi>They ſpend their temporall eſtates in ſpirituall livings.</hi> In the 14 P. he called <hi>tyths his temporals,</hi> and here he talks of ſpirituall livings, indeed he knowes not what to call them, but do great tyth-livings waſt ſo faſt, <hi>male parta, male dilabuntur,</hi> he ſaid, <hi>Their livings be their dying.</hi> And no wonder ſince they live on the dead things of the Law, and when they bury their living by tyths, if it pleaſed M.C. I will invite ſome gueſſe to the funerall: he tels us <hi>They be ſouldiers,</hi> and if they be Chriſts ſouldiers, they will be content with Chriſts pay, if they be not his ſouldiers, I will be none of their company.</p>
            <p>Then he finds fault, <hi>That men muzzle the Oxe till they make an Aſſe of him,</hi> Indeed God ſometimes makes fooliſh the wiſe things of this world, but if M.C. had been ſo mightily muzled, how could he have cryed out, this <hi>Hue and Cry,</hi> but it is true, that ſounds more like braying then any thing els. M. C. <hi>ſpeakes of the trouble of going to Law about tythes,</hi> he may ſave all that trouble, <note place="margin">
                  <hi>Fox</hi> 5</note> if he pleaſe to follow the example of the Primitive Miniſters. It was objected by a Popiſh Prieſt to Mr. <hi>Thorpe.</hi> How they ſhould live without law, who could hardly live by the Law of Tythes. To whom he replyed, no wonder, ſince people know that you live con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to Chriſt, and his Apoſtles; if you would not be maintained con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to Chriſt, the hearts of the people would be open. Mr. C. hints of the Kingdome of Chriſt being lookt upon for a Kingdome of fooles, for neglecting their livelihood. I thinke few of our Engliſh Tribe of Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vi are guilty of that folly; When they goe to a Benefice, the firſt queſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on is, <hi>How big is it, what is it worth?</hi> And the world without queſtion ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts Chriſts ſervants fooles, for their leaving father, mother, houſe and land for Chriſt, though ſome are ſo wiſe, as not to part with their Leviticall Patrimony for Chriſt. Then Mr. C. would have thoſe quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter ſouldiers that pay not tythes. And what if ſome ſhould be ſo here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticall in Mr. C. account as to judge it as equitable, that the Parſons (who do plead ſo much for hoſpitality) ſhould quarter every tenth ſouldier, having each tenth ſheafe of wheat for bread, and of barley for beer, and of fodder for horſe, and Piggs for their Suppers. Then Mr. C. tels us that Kings, Parliament and Biſhops, &amp;c. are cryed againſt for not
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:35265:11"/>better ſetling of Miniſters Livings out of alienated lands, and yet he could allow <hi>Barn. Sheafe</hi> the alienation of a Parſonage to be a witneſſe to his Tyth ſtory; though he ſaith, <hi>That for want of ſuch a maintenance there is the guilt of the blood of ſoules.</hi> O horrible impiety! what preachers have been more corrupt then thoſe who have been moſt richly maintain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, who have imbittered the waters of the Goſpel more then they with wormood and gall? who have ſtabbed more ſoules with the daggers of their own inventions? Then we are told of the <hi>Pious mind of the founders, and of the ſtones of the Abbies crying out</hi> &amp;c. Doth not his paper bluſh at this expreſſion? What, were Abby founders pious minded men now? what, were they not built for the Abbots and Monks to ſay Maſſe in. <hi>Willet</hi> in his <hi>Synopſis</hi> ſaith, ſpeaking of Monaſteries, the Lands which were beſtowed on them, were firſt given upon an evill intent, that the Monks by their prayers ſhould redeem the ſouls of their founders, who moſt of them had committed ſome notable ſin, and ſo <hi>pro remedio animarum,</hi> built them. King <hi>Ethelſtand</hi> for killing of his brother <hi>Edwin</hi> built two for his ſoule, &amp;c. ſurely, this is not religious founding. Did M.C. abuſe the pi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous minds of the ſounders at the Cathedrall window in <hi>Canterbury?</hi> Surely, if Sathan ſhould ſet ſome men on the Pinacle, and ſhew them the glory of the world, and ſay as he did to our Saviour, <hi>All theſe things will I give thee,</hi> if he ſhould be as good as his word he ſhould be a pious foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der. <hi>Mr.C.</hi> likes not to have his reward in money, it ſeems he would be his owne carver. But yet if the State will come up to his condition, they be allowed by him the honor to pay him his hire; Providing for the Country Clergy ſomewhat more then for the City, becauſe ſaith he their charge is more; In keeping horſe and ſervants for Markets, and Lectures, and Mill. It might have been added, and for the charges of the <hi>Hue and Cry;</hi> How gladly Mr. <hi>C.</hi> would have his ſervants and horſe weare the publike Livery. And ſo he drawes to a period, ſaying, that he prayes, a new way of concluding of <hi>Hue and cryes,</hi> and ſo he bids fare<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>well, but would not have us fare ſo well as to eat Tyth-piggs. And ſo farewell <hi>Paul</hi> untill I ſee you againe, Farewell <hi>Hue and Cry,</hi> I ſee no rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to follow thee with ſuch <hi>haſt haſt, poſt haſt.</hi> But goe thy wayes, and sunne, untill thou art out of breath, and then lye downe and breath thy laſt, and ſo conclude thy act with</p>
            <closer>Plaudite.</closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:35265:12"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:35265:12" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb facs="tcp:35265:13" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:35265:13"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb facs="tcp:35265:14" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:35265:14"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:35265:15"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:35265:15"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:35265:16"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:35265:16"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="8" facs="tcp:35265:17"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="9" facs="tcp:35265:17"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="10" facs="tcp:35265:18"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="11" facs="tcp:35265:18"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="12" facs="tcp:35265:19"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="13" facs="tcp:35265:19"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="14" facs="tcp:35265:20"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="15" facs="tcp:35265:20"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="16" facs="tcp:35265:21"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:35265:21"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="18" facs="tcp:35265:22"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb facs="tcp:35265:22"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
